Five digit bounties seemed to me like
something reserved for top hunters with
their crazy payloads. But recently, I made it.
I got a $20,000 bounty for a path traversal that
allowed me to leak files of other users. In
this video, I will show you what the bug was
and also why I think others have missed it so
make sure you stay until the end. But for now,
enjoy the explanation. I was short after listening
to a critical thinking episode with Alex Chapman
and my understanding of his methodology is that he
goes mostly for high and critical vulnerabilities.
But the thing is he goes for bugs that rely on
specific functionality. Because for example,
when you have an IDOR, an IDOR can be in almost
every single request or authorization bug.
But for a bug like SSRF, you need a specific
functionality. And my understanding of Alex's
methodology was that he goes for this
functionality. And I started looking at my
unnamed target because it's a private bug bounty
program with this approach in mind. So I wanted to
find some functionality where I can find high and
critical risk bugs. But really, there wasn't much.
There wasn't much interesting functionality. But
one that caught my attention was uploading files
because I could upload an avatar to my profile.
I saw that this target uses Amazon S3 buckets
and that they use the same bucket for avatars
and for other sensitive files that I as user can
upload. So I knew that any bug here will be very
impactful. And when it comes to the integration
with Amazon S3, there are a few options. One,
the conventional option would be that you send
a request to the server with your new profile
picture, and then the server talks with S3 sort of
in the backend, and then your new avatar is saved.
And maybe the user does not even see that the S3
is used. The problem with this approach is that it
is very consuming on the server because the server
sort of acts as a proxy between the S3 and the
user and its images, its other files, which are
quite heavy. So there is another way to do this
functionality. The ideal method would be to just
let the user talk directly with the S3 bucket,
bypassing the server, bypassing the need of server
to proxy the images. But then the problem you come
up to is how do you maintain an authorization when
the user talks directly to the bucket? Because
then I could just upload my avatars as avatar
of another user. I could maybe delete them.
I could at least read other people's files.
So this wouldn't be that good. That's why there
is the mechanism that's called pre-signed URLs.
And the way it works is I send the request to the
server, to my target, saying, hello, I'm Greg,
and I want to upload an avatar. I'm already
authenticated, so there is no problem with this.
And now the server responds with a URL, which
allows me to upload the file there. This URL
allows me to talk to the S3 API, and I can only
upload my file to a specified location. This
URL is signed cryptographically, so I cannot
mess up with these parameters. And then after
I send the request to the S3 API, I save my file
there. I confirm to my target server that, yes,
I have saved my file at this location which
you gave me. So this is a three-step process,
and it was robust. I couldn't do anything. I tried
uploading XSS files. I tried path traversals. It's
just nothing you can do here. When it comes to
this pre-signed URL, if you could break the SHA-1
signature, you could probably break half of the
internet. So this is also not happening. But the
three-step process is only uploading of the file,
and of course, the file has to be read somewhere.
That's why we upload it. So then when I go to
my account page, I see that the image tag with
my avatar, it has the pre-signed URL as well.
The difference is that this time, I didn't send
this request specifically for the pre-signed
URL. This time, the URL was just embedded in
the HTML of the response, and it contained
the link to my avatar, which I could request.
And the file name that was used here is the name
I used in step three previously. So my idea was,
what if I send here a file that does not belong
to me? And the first thing that I tried was an
avatar that I've uploaded from my other account,
and it worked. And I could see on my account page,
the avatar uploaded from another account, which
didn't have any impact yet, but it showed me that
there's probably no authorization check in place.
Then I moved one step ahead, and I, instead of
using the avatar, I used another document uploaded
from my another account, something I just uploaded
in another functionality of this application. And
when I went to the account page, my image did not
load. My image did not load, but the image tag
still had the pre-signed URL. And when I opened
it in the new tab, it did show me the document,
the sensitive document from my another account.
At this point, I was confident that this is
a valid bug and there is impact to it. But
the problem was that the name of the file from my
another account, I couldn't brute force it. It was
too complex to be brute forcible. So I wanted
to find a way to leak this to get the maximum
payout. I think if I reported the bug as it was,
I would get a payout, but probably as a P2 or P3,
and I wanted the maximum bounty. The thing with
pre-signed URLs is that they can point to a file,
but they can also point to a directory. So what
I did was, instead of using the file name in step
three, I just used the directory and I left it
this way. As always, I went to the account page,
my avatar didn't load, so I copied the pre-signed
URL from the image tag, pasted into the browser,
and I saw a lot of different files, which I saw
did not belong to me. Now, this funny problem I
had is even though there were thousand files,
because this is by default, the limit of AWS,
I didn't access any of them because I saw
that this is probably customer information,
but by file names, they didn't look as
sensitive as some of the files in the system.
So I found, I later found the AWS S3 parameters
that allow me to show more than 1,000 objects on
the directory listing or the object listing to
be precise. And at this point, I just knew that
this is a critical bug, and as expected, I got
the maximum payout. I was really happy with it,
especially that it came after quite a bad period
when it comes to bug bounty. More on this in the
bounty vlog, subscribe to not miss it, but it
just showed me that those big five-digit payouts,
there is no magic to them. It's just
persistency, continuous learning, and
putting in the time and the bugs just come. I
think the reason that others have missed this bug,
maybe because the pre-signed URL was hidden in the
HTML of the response. If there will be another API
call that would only return the pre-signed URL,
I'm pretty certain that then somebody would report
it before me because this attack is nothing new.
In fact, I did cover it on my channel in 2021. And
by the way, it's just nice confirmation to see on
my example and on your examples that the content
that I create is actually useful in real life and
gets me and gets you, my subscribers, bounties. If
you want to learn even more with me, I encourage
you to join BBRE Premium. Only until the end
of October, 2023, you can join for a monthly
subscription. After the end of October, there
will be only a yearly one. The reason is that it
just becomes too good of a deal that someone can
access all the articles in the archive by paying
$10 for a monthly subscription. So if you want to
join before this, go to BBRE.dev slash premium.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye.